# Peter Solfest

Northrop Grumman Corporation, 3200 Samson Way, Bellevue, NE 68123

peter.solfest@ngc.com (651) 325-8903 Clearance Level: Secret

# Summary

I develop and engineers software solutions using state-of-the-art techniques and technologies. I am interested in positions that leverage my MBSE, coding and DevSecOps expertise. I am also fascinated by using software to solve and model applied/computational math and physics problems.

# Professional Experience

Northrop Grumman Mathematician SWAFS, Weather and Space Impacts Research and Development Center Feb 2017 - present

- Roles: SWAFS Tech Lead, SWAFS Software Developer, Research Assistant

**Engineering Scientist Associate** 

Space and Geophysics Laboratory

Research Assistant

Dept. of Computer Science

Calculus Instructor

Calculus 1 and 2

Applied Research Laboratories, UT

Oct 2015 - Jan 2017

University of Minnesota

July 2014 - Mar 2015

Michigan Tech Dept. of Mathematics

Jan 2013 - June 2014 (4 semesters)

## **Professional Certifications**

Caltech DevOps Post Graduate Program Certificate Caltech CTME

cloud-native development and agile operations Ongoing (Nov 2020 - May 2021)

CSSLP (Member ID: 788005)  $(ISC)^2$ 

secure software throughout development lifecycle Oct 2020 - Sep 2023

Model-Based Systems Engineering Caltech CTME

SysML training and model creation 2019

System Engineering Fundamentals Caltech CTME

Practical methods and tools for system engineering 2019

CompTIA Security+

Application, network, and device security Feb 2018 - Feb 2021

### Education

Michigan Technological University Houghton, MI

M.S. in Applied Mathematics; GPA: 4.00 Aug 2012 - June 2014

Michigan Technological University Houghton, MI

B.S. in Physics and Applied/Computational Mathematics; GPA:3.94 Aug 2008 - Apr 2012

### Software Skills

• Practices: Agile methodologies, unit testing, multi-language development, DevSecOps, Software Modeling

- Tools: Fortify, GitHub, git, Jenkins, JIRA, LaTeX, Linux, Make, MATLAB, Maven, mercurial, SharePoint, SonarQube
- Languages: BASH, C, C++, Fortran (Modern and 77), Java, JavaScript, Python, SysML, SQL

## Achievements

NG IP trade secret awards

3 related to space and weather effects on communications

MS IP Committee

2018-2019

**Outstanding Teaching Award** 

Michigan Tech Dept. of Mathematics

Graduate Level 2014